[theme music playing]
[objects clattering]
[sighs]
[Mickey] Fuck!
Oh, shit!
[scrubbing]
Hey!
-Hi. Oh, no...
-Hi.
-Don't step there.
-Oh, shit.
-[Mickey] I gotta sweep that up.
-Sorry.
Hey, did you notice last night,
there was a point where I was spooning you
[chuckles] and then
you were spooning Grandpa?
It was so cute.
Oh, my God!
Bertie leaves half-eaten
yogurt cups in here.
Who eats half a yogurt
and then puts it back?
She is a small person, so...
Can I help? Why are you cleaning?
Oh, well, my dad's coming to town,
so I figured I'd clean.
Your dad? Really?
Marty Dobbs, flying in from Jersey
as we speak.
Wow. I had no idea.
Well, he didn't tell me until yesterday.
My dad's Mr. Casual.
But it's cool.
It'll be good to see him, I think.
That's cool.
I'm sure you guys will have a fun time.
-[Mickey] Hmm.
-Um...
you, uh, guys got any big plans?
[sighs] Well, I was gonna meet him
for lunch near the airport
and bring him back here.
-Hmm.
-You should come with.
Oh! Uh, wow, okay, um...
-It'll be fun!
-[inhales sharply]
Please, please, please.
Free lunch on Marty Dobbs.
What else are you gonna do today, hmm?
I don't know. I just...
I don't wanna intrude on time
with your dad and...
Meeting a dad's kind of a big deal,
don't you think?
Dude, no. It is so not a big deal.
If you meet my mom, that's a big deal.
This will be easy.
My dad's kind of an asshole,
but you'll like him and he'll love you.
I mean,
compared to all the other guys he's met.
The last guy was on cat tranquilizers.
-Those work on humans?
-Yeah.
Same as human ones.
You gotta take a bunch.
[chuckles]
So, what do you say, Cruikshank?
Are you in?
Uh...
okay.
Yes, fine.
Why not?
I'll meet Poppa Dobbs. Sure.
Sweet! I'm gonna take a quick shower,
and we'll hit the road.
Okay. All right.
Oh, hey, Gus.
Bertie. Morning.
Why is everything different?
Oh, uh, Mickey's cleaning up. Yeah.
I guess her dad's visiting.
-He is?
-Yeah.
And, uh, I'm gonna go meet him.
-Oh, wow! For real?
-Mmm-hmm.
You think it's too soon?
Hmm. I don't know.
That's a good question.
-Oh, where'd my yogurt go?
-That's also a good question.
Do you know where it went?
No.
[music playing over radio]
-[Gus] You look nice.
-[Mickey] Glad I showered.
Oh, me too.
It would've been a bad first impression
to meet your dad with me,
like, reeking of sex.
-[Mickey] Hmm.
-[chuckles]
Yeah. That's probably something
dads can smell instinctively anyway.
[chuckling]
Got any, uh, tips on meeting your dad?
Anything I should know going in?
-Mmm, not really.
-Yeah? What's he do for a living?
He used to be a dentist,
before he lost his license for giving out,
uh, prescriptions of pain medications.
Oh. Okay.
Now he's a consultant,
whatever that means.
-Hmm.
-He's always about to make a ton of money
on some amazing idea
that always falls through.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
When's the... when's the last time
you guys saw each other?
Two, three years ago.
Oh. Shit. So this is...
this is kind of a big deal.
I mean, it's not not a big deal,
but it's not a big deal.
Do you two not...
Like, I don't know what...
Do you guys not get along, or...
No, it's not that. I mean, we're just,
you know, both busy people.
I mean, he's my dad,
so it'll always be a little complicated,
but we're not, like,
estranged or anything.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, don't worry,
dads are kind of my specialty.
A lot of times an ex's dad will like me
more than his daughter ever did.
That's fucked up.
Yeah, I realize that's probably
not something I should brag about.
I'm guessing it's more of a turn on
to be the bad boy anyway, right?
Not for me anymore.
Where is he? I mean, his plane landed,
like, an hour ago.
Yeah. Uh, I wouldn't worry about it.
You know, it probably takes a long time
getting off the plane,
and picking up your bags and...
waiting in line for those taxis and stuff.
-[Mickey] That's probably him.
-[Gus] Oh, yup.
-Oh, shit.
-[Marty] Thank you.
-Hey, Dad!
-[chuckles] Hey, kiddo! How are ya?
Aw. Man, you're even skinnier
than the last time I saw you.
[chuckles] Ah, you look
pretty good yourself.
Yeah, I do, don't I? [chuckles]
-Hello! Hi.
-Hey.
Sorry. This is Gus. He's...
Uh, we're dating.
Nice to meet you, Marty.
-[chuckling]
-Sorry, I'm a hugger.
-Gus, huh?
-Yeah.
I only ever knew one other Gus.
Gus Greenwold. Solid guy.
Oh, yeah.
I think I, uh, met him last year
at the, uh, Gus Convention.
He's not alive.
Oh. [chuckles] Um, I'm sorry.
Well, that's okay. I mean, at least
we're all still here, am I right?
-Yeah!
-[both chuckling]
-Hey, can I take those for you?
-Uh, yeah.
Thank you. I mean...
-Eager little guy.
-Yeah.
Isn't this place cool, Dad?
It's Himalayan.
They're supposed to have
the best samosas in LA.
Well, that's a bold statement, Mick.
You know how picky I am about my samosas.
[all chuckling]
So, uh, Marty, how was the flight?
[scoffs] Oh, my God.
They sat me next to a lady
with one of these therapy dogs.
You heard about this?
It's just a bullshit excuse for this lady
-to bring her bichon everywhere.
-[chuckles]
I know. Therapy dogs. It's like, really?
Right after we take off,
we hit a little turbulence.
This dog goes crazy.
Starts barking and whimpering
and immediately takes a dump...
-Oh, my God.
-on the floor.
-No!
-It smells disgusting.
I mean, they clean it up,
but for five full hours,
I am in dog shit hell.
People start looking at me
like it's my dog.
-That's awful!
-And I'm saying,
"Hey," you know, "Do I look like I'm
a fucking bichon owner to you?"
-No. You don't.
-[chuckling]
-You really don't... Yeah.
-Oh, thank you.
Mick, you still got that cat?
What's his name?
Grandpa. 'Cause he's the reincarnation
of Grandpa, remember?
Yeah. This is what makes Mickey Mickey.
[Marty and Gus chuckle]
Oh, Dad, um, I got a promotion at work.
I'm a program manager now
at the radio station.
Really?
Hey, congratulations!
Hey, you always were good
at hustling up work.
-Thanks.
-You and me, huh? Both hustlers.
See, there's something good
you inherited from me.
It's in our blood.
Right. Yeah.
[Gus chuckles]
[sighs] So, Gus, what's your last name?
-Cruikshank. Mmm-hmm.
-Cruikshank.
[chuckles] What nationality is that?
Oh, it's, um, Scottish. German.
Uh, you know, I... I gotta say,
I figured that you were maybe, uh--
-What? Jewish?
-Mmm-hmm.
Ah! [chuckling]
Yeah, I get that sometimes.
'Cause of the, uh... [exclaims]
[both laughing]
No, no, I was, uh,
I was actually raised Catholic.
-Well, you had me fooled.
-[chuckles] Good.
Gus was raised in South Dakota
and he teaches kid actors.
No kidding.
Have you ever heard of the show Witchita?
Yeah, the witch show, you bet.
Gus worked on that show.
-And... he wrote a script for them.
-Ah...
-No! Hey, well, that's great!
-[Gus softly] Yeah.
Great.
Good for you, Micks.
Got yourself a nice, hardworking guy
with no tattoos or piercings.
[Mickey and Gus chuckle]
I had a feeling you two would get along.
Better than the last guy.
Remember when he fell asleep at the table?
-[Gus chuckles awkwardly]
-Have you decided?
[chuckles] Well, I've decided
that you are a ray of sunshine.
What's your name?
Pema.
Pema, beautiful Pema, huh?
How's your day?
-[Pema] It's good.
-Good, good.
Good, all right, well, we are gonna
start off with a couple orders of samosas.
And the tandoori shrimp,
uh, steamed momo,
the lamb tikka masala...
and the chicken vindaloo.
Good choices.
Uh, are you sure, Dad?
That's a lot of food.
I live large.
Don't worry, lunch is on me.
Hey, thank you.
So, uh, what brings you into town?
Oh, well, Southwest doesn't fly direct
to San Francisco from where I live.
But I'm heading up to Palo Alto.
Got a meeting with an investor I think
is going to help me out
with this new app I've got.
Oh, okay.
What's the... what's the idea?
It's like Uber, but better.
[stutters] You know, it's the better Uber.
[chuckles]
These things are
all about right place, right time.
I mean, I've had guys rip me off,
make money off my ideas,
but that is not gonna happen this time.
Well, uh, I just wanna say, we're so glad
to have you in town and, uh,
maybe I'll get to find out
a little bit more about
what this one was like as a kid, huh?
-You got any, uh, funny stories?
-Oh, my God, where to begin?
-No. No, no.
-Oh, never mind. Forget it. Yeah.
-She ever tell you about the whip-its?
-Oh! Dad, come on.
Seventh grade.
Her mother has to pick her up from school,
because she has been busted doing whip-its
in the parking lot at 11:00 a.m.
Mickey, you little scamp. [chuckles]
That was a long time ago.
It was hard to punish her,
because we've all done whip-its, right?
[chuckles nervously] All the time.
She ever tell you about the time
she got out of the car
in the middle of the night?
Uh, I don't think so,
but you don't have to... tell me.
So, I'm driving her home, right?
It's late. It's dark. I'm tired.
She's in the back. What are you, like, 13?
No, I was 11.
Either way, she will not stop complaining.
I don't even remember
what she was talking about,
but she is bitching and moaning
and I finally just say,
"Hey, if you don't behave,
I'm pulling over."
-Classic dad move.
-But when I pull up at the light...
this kid gets out.
That's not exactly
how I remember it, but--
I am talking middle of the night,
Jersey City.
Homeless people, drunks.
God knows what kind of dangerous people
wandering around.
I'm yelling at her,
"Hey, get back in here!"
-[Gus chuckling]
-Of course, she doesn't listen.
So I spent the rest of the night
looking for her,
thinking she'd been kidnapped
or God knows what.
And then I find her...
at a Burger King,
eating french fries and having a ball.
-[chuckles]
-[Gus] Wow, that's a crazy story.
This one's always been
a little troublemaker.
We tell her to do something,
she does the opposite.
But that's what we love about her.
[inhales deeply]
Lord knows she's had to put up
with my shit too, so... [chuckles]
Mmm.
Beautiful Pema, what have you got for us?
-Samosas...
-Mmm-mmm.
That's good.
Oh, yeah! Looking good!
Yeah, I think I'm going to, uh,
go wash the airplane off my hands.
I'll be right back.
Fuck him.
I'm so tired of his shit.
He loves telling
that stupid fucking story.
[sighs] I'm sorry. I feel like I'm the one
who told him to tell it, so...
You want to know
why I was so upset that night?
It's because I missed
my best friend's birthday party,
because I spent the whole day
sitting in the lobby of his office
while he pitched some shady business deal.
When he stopped the car,
he was yelling at me,
so when he told me to get out,
I thought he was serious,
because I was 11 years old!
So I got out and then he just drove away.
Oh, and he'll tell you that it was,
you know, just around the block.
But he fucking left me there.
And I was just sitting there, by myself,
on the corner, in the dark,
for what felt like forever.
So I just walked to a Burger King
and sat in the corner and cried.
And I have never been
so scared in my life.
[sighs]
Mickey, that's awful.
Yep.
Look, I don't know
if this will make you feel better,
but, you know, lot of times,
when we're kids,
we feel things, like,
a little more severely than what's real.
Are you taking his side?
No, no. I'm just saying...
stuff like this is always,
like, super complicated, you know?
It's like that thing they say,
"It's corny, but it's true."
It's like our parents know
which buttons to push,
because they're the ones
who installed them.
Dude, you don't have to fix everything.
Okay? Jesus! Whatever!
I just... All I ever wanted...
[sighs] Forget it.
[sighs]
[Marty sighs]
All righty, let me at this food!
-[Mickey] Mmm.
-[Marty chuckling]
Mmm.
A little bland.
[Gus] Well, that was excellent.
-Yes.
-Should I box this up?
Oh, nah.
Here, uh... Here's the card.
-Thanks, Dad.
-Yeah, thanks, Marty.
Yeah, well, I've had better vindaloo,
but I liked it okay.
Do you wanna come back to my place?
Get settled in?
Didn't you get my text?
-I don't think so.
-No?
Oh, maybe it didn't go through.
No, uh, my plans changed.
I'm on the 8:00 p.m.
to San Francisco tonight.
I figured I'd get up there early,
get a good night's sleep
before the big meeting.
Oh, okay.
I mean, don't you want to
just come see where I live?
It's the first nice place
I've ever lived in.
Oh, sweetheart, I came to see you,
not your place.
Do you really want to spend three hours
in a car,
driving across town?
I'd rather just, you know,
find some place.
We could sit and talk.
I'll see your place next time.
Okay, yeah. That makes sense.
[inhales deeply]
All right, where to now?
Yeah, uh, what do you think, Mickey?
Hey, let's get a drink, huh?
Celebrate.
-[Gus] Hmm.
-Celebrate what?
Us. [chuckles] Life. My new business.
All good things, huh?
What, do we need a reason to celebrate?
Yeah, um, maybe we could go to that,
uh, donut place that's around here?
It's pretty awesome.
They got all these crazy flavors,
like marshmallow and basil, but...
it's not gross like I'm making it sound.
[chuckles] I don't want a donut.
We just ate.
Right, right, right. Uh... [stammers]
What about a museum?
There's an exhibit around here
that's about medieval torture devices.
-Could be really fun, I think?
-Yeah. Yeah, come on, you need a drink.
-Over here.
-[Gus] Okay.
[door chimes]
[sighs] Hello.
Uh, you guys grab a table.
I'll get some drinks, okay?
-[Gus] Okay.
-This place reeks.
-What's your name?
-Carol.
-Carol, huh? Beautiful Carol.
-Yes.
-Ah...
-Marty Dobbs. How are you?
-Marty Dobbs, how are you?
-What are you drinking?
I hate this.
I hate everything about this.
What... [sighs]
What am I doing in a bar?
Yeah. Are you okay?
You, um... You tempted or...
No. I don't... [sighing]
-I don't know!
-[laughing]
Well, here's to you, Jersey girl!
I don't wanna watch him drink
during the day. He's an alcoholic.
You think so?
He got a DUI when I was in high school
and had his license suspended.
He had to go to court-mandated AA.
You know what, let's get out of here.
Tell him we wanna go.
No, let's just stay.
It's not worth it to piss off Marty Dobbs.
Whatever you need,
I'm here for you, okay?
Seriously.
[Marty] Can you believe this?
You see that lady over there?
Her name's Carol.
She grew up two towns away from me
and here we are, meeting in a bar in LA.
-What are the chances of that?
-[glasses clink]
-Serendipity.
-All righty.
Gussy, grab your glass!
Mickle the pickle. [sighs]
And one for the pops.
Here's to my beautiful daughter
and to Gus.
Love you, Mick.
Hey, come on, it's bad luck not to cheers.
Come on.
Hey! All right.
I don't really feel like a beer,
so I'm gonna go smoke.
I could never figure out that kid's moods.
[chuckles] God bless you, if you can.
Uh, I just try to listen.
You should ask her how she's doing.
I think, uh, it might turn things
around a bit.
I don't get it. I mean,
I come here, and she gets all quiet.
[scoffs]
Won't even have a beer with her dad.
Hmm, well,
I wouldn't take it too personally.
I think she's, um...
She wants to, but...
What?
Well... she's sober.
Sober?
Yeah, like, um, you know,
in the... in the program.
-AA, huh?
-Yeah.
Again. [chuckles]
Well, good luck with that, Micks.
I think it's really good for her.
-Sweetheart, can I bum a smoke?
-Sure. Here you go.
-Best happy hour in the city, this place.
-That's awesome.
Three-dollar well drinks.
Only problem is it doesn't start
for two more hours.
Carol got here too early.
[chuckles]
-I'm Carol. [snorts and laughs]
-Oh.
You got yourself a good daddy.
Oh, yeah, he's a real great guy.
He sure is.
He came all the way out here to see you.
Lucky girl.
Carol, your, uh, nipple's out.
Oh, whoopsies!
Whoops.
[music playing]
Hey, you know, Gus, I think I saw
a jukebox over there.
Why don't you go
pick us out some tunes, huh?
Oh, I don't want
to waste your money, Marty.
Who knows how long it'll take
to play the song?
I'm not nervous.
Go for it, bud.
Uh... [exhales slowly] okay.
Cool. Be right back.
So, Mick?
Gus told me something interesting.
Oh, what's that?
He says you're in AA.
He told you that?
Why would you do that to yourself again?
Because I have a problem.
AA is just a load of bullshit.
You know how I feel about this.
[stammers] That is for people
that cannot think for themselves.
AA was started by a bunch of evangelicals
who were fuck-ups.
But they want to make us feel
like we got the problem.
I don't have a problem.
You don't have a problem.
They just want to make you think you do.
I am an alcoholic, Dad.
I need help.
AA is helping me.
Hmm. Yeah. All right, let me guess.
You go to the meetings
and you complain about your dad?
Is that it, huh?
It's all my fault?
-[Gus groans softly]
-Jesus, Mickey.
I raised you to use your brain.
Not join a cult!
Hey, Marty, I just want to say...
you have an amazing daughter.
And you should be so proud of her.
Mmm. Thank you for saying that, Gus.
That means a lot, coming from a guy
I hadn't even heard about
until an hour ago.
Okay. All right.
Let's just take a breath here.
Gus, just stay out of it, okay? Jesus.
[Marty] AA.
[scoffing] Oh, my God.
Fuck.
[inhales deeply]
So tell me about your app, Dad.
Well...
it's called the R Car.
It's a high-end car service
that comes and picks you up.
So, it's exactly like Uber?
No. No, because you can reserve
your car in advance.
That's what the R stands for.
You can't do that with Uber.
Well, there are Ubers around all the time,
so you don't need to reserve them.
What about after a sporting event? Huh?
What about at the airport?
I've never had to wait
for more than four minutes for an Uber.
We also have great cars.
They got bottles of water and mints
and iPhone jacks.
You can charge your phone,
play your music.
Yeah, Uber's got all of that.
And... and you can pick the kind of car
you want to get.
Oh, that's cool.
So, could I get, like, a Ferrari?
[chuckles]
Well, maybe not a Ferrari.
But, uh--
So it's exactly like Uber.
[scoffs]
[glass thuds]
[chuckles]
Uh, you know what, I...
-I should probably get going. Yeah.
-[Mickey] Mmm.
I gotta get back to the airport,
get checked in.
I might as well get there early.
Get situated.
Ah, but your flight's not
for another few hours.
Oh, no, no, no. You should go now.
Get situated. Uh, do you want a ride?
-No, I'm fine.
-We should call you a taxi,
'cause you probably
wouldn't want to take an Uber, huh?
That's a good one.
Yeah. I got to go square up.
How's Uncle Tim?
[scoffs]
Still a fuck-up.
[Gus] Here we go. Okay.
Marty, let me give you these.
-All right.
-Okay.
Good luck up there!
-Thanks.
-Okay.
All right. Bye, Micks.
Don't be a stranger.
Love you.
[chuckles] I love you, too.
All right.
[Mickey sighs]
Why would you tell my dad that I'm sober?
Do you know how fucked up that is,
to break somebody's anonymity?
-To their dad?
-Okay. I was trying to help.
I didn't want your help.
Your help is not helping.
I just wanted you
to be a buffer between us.
That's what I thought I was doing.
I wanted him to see I was grown up
and I had my shit together and maybe,
maybe he would just treat me differently.
And we could have a decent day for once.
But it was the same thing.
It's always gonna be the same.
You don't know that.
Things change.
People change.
I almost got through one day with him
without a fight.
But then you had to go
and fucking tell him about AA
and he got all pissed off.
That is so fucked up, Gus!
I can't even be in a car
with you right now.
Oh, my God...
Mickey, come on!
-Jesus Christ.
-[door slams]
[Mickey] Fuck.
-Mickey, wait!
-[sighs]
Come on!
Come on, just wait. Hold on.
[sighs] Oh, God.
Just...
Do you really fucking need
people to like you that badly?
I'm the one who should matter to you.
Not him.
"Oh, Marty, you're so funny."
[sighs] You should have stood up for me.
I tried, but you told me to, like...
-Oh, Jesus. Just stop it!
-It's very confusing for me.
You want me... your dad to like me.
Am I supposed to have him hate me?
Do I... What?
Shut the fuck up!
I'm sorry. Okay? [sighs]
[sighs]
I know I messed up, and...
I'm truly sorry.
I'm sorry too.
I'm... [sighs]
It's really not you. It's him.
He was shitty to you.
It's okay to be upset.
I'll give you a ride home
so you can get a break from me.
I don't want a break from you.
Okay?
[Mickey sighs]
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh, my God, that could be my dad's plane.
Fuck you!
Yeah. Fuck you, Marty!
['60s rock music playing]